Matthew Bogard

□ matthewkbogard@gmail.com

mbogard.com

(512) 961-9526

Austin, TX 78704



Proficient Technologies

JavaScript

React.js, Redux & React Native

Node.js

HTML

CSS

Express.js

iQuerv

SOL

Docker

WordPress API & Pantheon

Testing Frameworks (Jest, AVA, & Cypress)

Amazon Web Services

Terraform

Java, Spring Boot

Python

PHP

SUMMARY

Ambitious and knowledgeable full-stack software developer. Proficient in creating modern frontend applications, interacting with back-end APIs, and managing applications using cloud services and database scripts. I can confidently jump into a complicated existing code base, or build new sustainable apps that use intuitive logic. Embraces opportunities to collaborate and expand technical expertise.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer, Passport, Inc. - March 2021-Present

• Comprehensive contributor to enforcement products including projects in React.js and Node.js as well as Java, PHP, and SQL

Software Engineer, Red Ventures - December 2018-March 2021

- Built business-critical, revenue impacting applications from the ground up as well as created features and fixed bugs for existing applications
- Contributed to every stage of the development process—from the initial project management discussions of a new feature all the way to its final implementation in production
- Created and maintained many integral internal apps and tools for owned websites using JavaScript, specifically React and Node.js
- Established Amazon Web Services infrastructure for applications using Terraform code
- Improved APIs central to revenue, specifically APIs written in Java's Spring framework
- Managed a Content Management System for thousands of editorial articles using WordPress API as well as Python and Node.js scripts

Texas Health & Human Services, Rate Analysis Department - Jan 2017-Jun 2018

- Promoted to Project Manager after 12 months Directed projects related to programming Texas Medicare & Medicaid rates for the department of 150 employees
- Rate Analyst Wrote, reviewed, and refined SPSS code used for calculating annual changes in Texas Medicare & Medicaid rates

EDUCATION

Full-Stack Web Development Certification, The University of Texas at Austin - 2018 Earned Certificate and Completed the Coding Bootcamp Program

Bachelor's Degree, The University of Texas at Austin - Graduated 2016 Bachelor of Arts in Government, Minor in Rhetoric and Writing Cumulative GPA: 3.5

SKILLS

- Comprehensive team contributor, from helping Platform teams effectively run their cloud services to assisting QA teams automate their testing suites
- Knowledgeable manager of repositories with Git version control as well as a proficient user of powerful CLI tools, IDEs including all JetBrains products, and GUIs like Postman

VIEW MORE

- https://www.linkedin.com/in/matthew-bogard/
- o https://us-census-data.herokuapp.com/
- o https://mbogard.com/music/
- o https://medium.com/@mbogard/what-coding-bootcamps-dont-teach-c71c3182f11